

# Jude Uzochukwu Iwuagwu

St. Veit Gasse, 52-54 1/2 1130 Wien Mobile: +436604022807

Email: <u>uzoiwuagwu@gmail.com</u>
Github: https://github.com/uzotex

#### **Personal statement**

A highly experienced and creative web developer with over 7 years' experience in a variety of exciting projects. A level head and rational approach to problem solving combined with a passion for innovative and fresh ideas has led to a portfolio of impressive web app solutions. Technically competent and industry aware means that each project is undertaken with the most up-to-date and relevant programming foundations available.

#### **Core skills**

- Knowledge of JavaScript, CSS, HTML5, C# and JavaScript
- Experience with design pattern, frameworks and architecture (Laravel, BootStrap Apache ASP.NET and Microsoft SharePoint)
- Working knowledge of SQL, Google-analytics, Oracle and MySQL
- Experienced with OS Linux- Ubuntu and Microsoft Windows
- Experience with object-oriented software development methodologies Agile and Scrum
- Integrating new technologies into web properties

# **Employment history**

### Freelance Full stack Developer

#### (May 2017 - Present)

Presently a member of the Free Code Camp non- profit organisation, contributing on projects for non-profitable organisation.

Design and maintenance of website

Masters Research Topic

#### Software Solution Architect - Phillips Consulting

#### (August 2013 – April 2017)

#### **Duties**

- Developing and maintaining the front end functionality of websites.
- Participating in discussions with clients to clarify what they want.
- Designing prototypes for apps and websites.
- Creating logos, banners and buttons for websites.
- Writing cross-browser compliant XHTML, CSS & JavaScript.
- Simultaneously managing several databases and reporting tools.
- Contacting external webmasters to confirm link placements.
- Provide guidance to other team members on web development issues.
- Developing websites that have a consistent feel and look throughout all web properties.
- Providing technical support to end users.
- Identifying and correcting software deficiencies.
- Devising SEO strategies based around specific keywords

#### Microsoft SharePoint Support Analyst – MTN Telecommunication

(March 2010 – August 2013)

#### Duties

- Assisted senior architects in developing current and to-be systems architecture artifacts.
- Helped analyze legacy applications and systems to derive required business functions and rules from existing applications.
- Creating and customizing automated/workflow forms.
- Assigning permissions or roles to staff
- Migrated SharePoint 2007 to 2010
- Training Staff on the use of SharePoint for collaboration
- Training Staff on the use of any deployed Microsoft Applications;
- Assisting the Sales team in organizing Presentations to enhance sales;
- Assisting Project managers in assigning duties to team members;
- Developing technical and user guide documents for users;
- Working with the Business Analyst and Project manager to ensure smooth design and implementation of any Microsoft Application;
- Delivering Functional and User Acceptance Testing;
- Involved in workshops, training and presentations.

# **Education**

# **FACHHOCHSCHULE TECHNIKUM WIEN**

(2016 – till date)

Masters Information System Management

# FREE CODE CAMP - http://www.freecodecamp.com

(2017 – till date)

Full stack development in JavaScript, Node.JS, JQuery, Jason, and MongoDB

# **LGIT SOLUTION - SOUTH AFRICA**

(2011)

Microsoft SharePoint 2010 Application Development

#### NNAMDI AZIKIWE UNIVERSITY- AWKA

(2004 - 2008)

B.Sc. Computer Science

# References

Please do not hesitate to contact me if you require references from any of my previous employers.